5/417, Echampatti, Rayakottai, Krishnagiri, Tamil Nadu-635116 + 91-9786146414 <u>rajsram.github.io</u> RajeshSivasankaran@outlook.com

## RAJESH SIVASANKARAN

### **PROFILE SUMMARY**

Having **5.9 years** of experience in analysis, design, development of windows, web, and mobile-based application.

Experience in development of .Net framework and Core, Angular, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, SQL, and Azure.

Self-learning of React, Node JS and python.

Effective in working independently and collaboratively in teams.

Code managing with TFS, Azure DevOps and GitHub.

A self-motivated person with the ability to learn new technologies and adapt to new environment.

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Client Side	HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Typescript, Angular and React
Server Side	C#.Net, ASP.Net MVC, .Net Core, Web API, Node Js
Databases	MSSQL, MySQL.
Cloud	Azure, App Service, VM, Blob and Key vault
Mobile	Ionic, Android and IOS (customize)

# PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Senior Software Engineer, Zeiss India, Bengaluru, Karnataka.

zeiss.com

Jul 2018 - Till

Software Engineer, Mindteck (India) Limited (Zeiss India),

Bengaluru, Karnataka.

mindteck.com

Aug 2017 - Jul 2018

Software Engineer, Cogwave software Technologies Pvt. Ltd, Bengaluru, Karnataka.

cogwave.in

Jun 2016 - Jul 2017

Software Engineer, Sivasakthi Software Services Pvt. Ltd, Coimbatore, Tamilnadu.

sivasakthisoft.com

Jul 2014 - May 2016

## **EDUCATION** Master of Computer Applications (MCA)

2011 - 2014

**Bachelor of Computer Applications (BCA)** 

2008 - 2014

**Higher Secondary Certificate (HSC)** 

2006 - 2008

**Secondary School Leaving Certificate (SSLC)** 

2006

## **PROJECTS**

Project Name	Online Update System
Duration	Jul 2018 – Till
Team size	7
Technologies	.Net Core WebAPI, HTML, CSS, Angular 6 and Azure
Role	Developer & Minor release lead
Responsibilities	UI from scratch, Web API, Database and Collaborate with global team

Project Name	Primus
Duration	Aug 2017 – Jul 2018
Team size	5
Technologies	ASP.Net MVC & WebApi2 HTML & CSS & JavaScript & jQuery Angular 5
Role	Developer
Responsibilities	UI & Service & Bug Fixing Coordinated all updates with TFS

Project Name	HMS (Hotel Management System)
Duration	Apr 2017 – Jul 2017
Team size	2
Technologies	ASP.Net MVC 5 & WebApi2 Dapper ORM & Autofac Kendo UI HTML & CSS & JavaScript & jQuery MS SQL Server
Role	Full Stack Developer

Responsibilities	UI & Service & Bug Fixing & Stored Procedures	
	Coordinated all updates with TFS	

Project Name	eKOT – POS
Duration	Mar 2017 – Apr 2017
Team size	2
Technologies	ASP.Net WebAPI 2 Dapper ORM & Autofac & Fluent Validation Angular 2 & Ionic 2 & TypeScript & Cordova MS SQL Server
Role	Full Stack Developer
Responsibilities	Design UI & Service & Bug Fixing Coordinated all updates with TFS

Project Name	House Keeping - HMS (Hotel Management System)
Duration	Feb 2017 – Mar 2017
Team size	3
Technologies	ASP.Net MVC 5 & WebApi2 Dapper ORM & Autofac HTML & Material CSS & JavaScript & jQuery MS SQL Server
Role	Full Stack Developer
Responsibilities	UI & Server Code & Bug Fixing & Stored Procedures Coordinated all updates with TFS

Project Name	Online Reporting - HMS (Hotel Management System)
Duration	Jan 2017 – Feb 2017
Team size	3
Technologies	ASP.Net MVC 5 & WebApi2 Dapper ORM & Autofac HTML & Material CSS & JavaScript & jQuery MS SQL Server
Role	Full Stack Developer
Responsibilities	UI & Code Development & Bug Fixing Stored Procedures Coordinated all updates with TFS

Project Name	HIS (Hospital Information System)
Duration	Jul 2016 – Dec 2016
Team size	5

Technologies	ASP.Net WebApi2 Dapper ORM & Autofac & Fluent Validation Angular 2 & TypeScript & HTML & Bootstrap CSS MS SQL Server
Role	Full Stack Developer
Responsibilities	UI & Code Development & Bug Fixing Stored Procedures Coordinated all updates with TFS

<b>Project Name</b>	SS KOT
Duration	Feb 2016 – May 2016
Team size	2
Technologies	ASP.Net WebApi2 & Entity Framework ORM HTML & CSS & JavaScript & Cordova MS SQL Server
Role	Full Stack Developer
Responsibilities	UI & Code Development & Bug Fixing

Project Name	Chit Fund Management
Duration	Jul 2015 – Feb 2016
Team size	4
Technologies	ASP.Net MVC & Entity Framework ORM & Dev Express HTML & CSS & JavaScript & jQuery MS SQL Server
Role	Full Stack Developer
Responsibilities	Database and Coding & Code Review Reporting with Team Leader Bug Fixing and Coordinated all updates

Project Name	Finance/Accounts Maintenance
Duration	Jul 2014 – Jul 2015
Team size	5
Technologies	VB.Net Dev Express MS SQL & MySQL
Role	Developer
Roles & Responsibilities	Reporting with Team Leader Bug Fixing Coordinated all updates Custom module development Customer Support